

Amanda Jane Murphy

amanda.jane.murphy@sap.com

087 9344138



PROFILE

Experienced Global HANA Product Support Engineer with over 14 years' experience working in the IT industry.

Role includes providing excellent technical support for SAP HANA Database customers using Cloud and On-Premise landscapes, on a global scale. Responsibilities include the creation of technical documentation and problem-solving with real-time support.

Project leader, with a team of 16 engineers, driving Continuous Improvement methodology for SAP Product Support in Ireland.

Keen interest in progressing into a leadership and management role.

EDUCATION

2018 to Date - Technology University Dublin

- B. Sc. Hons. Degree in I.T. Management with Data Analytics

2014 Graduate - Institute of Technology, Tallaght

- Bachelor of Science Degree in I.T. Management (Distinction)

Sep 2012 to Dec 2012 - Institute of Technology, Tallaght

- Certificate in Software Fundamentals (Java programming)

1991-1983 - Institute of Technology Carlow

National Certificate in Computing

Final 3rd Year Project An Investigation into the Suitable Application of the NoSQL Database.

I.T Skills:

Databases: HANA, Oracle, MySql, SqlServer, MongoDB, Sybase

Languages: Java, Unix Shell Scripting, R

Operating Systems HP-UX, Oracle-Solaris, AIX, Linux, Windows, Windows Azure VM,

Applications Tableau, Bootstrap, SAP BW, S/4 HANA, SAP Leonardo,

Articulate Storyline, Weka, JIRA, Skype for Business, Sharepoint,

Bootstrap

Professional Experience

2014 - date	SAP - Global HANA Product Support Engineer
2004 – 2014	Career break from IT – Part-time Customer Service position
2001 – 2004	Hewlett Packard Manufacturing Ltd - Oracle DBA
1993 – 2000	Norwich Union Insurance PLC – Oracle DBA and Unix Admin

Key Responsibilities

- Project Leader driving Continuous Improvement for GSC Ireland, leading a team of 16 engineers.
- Mentoring of new members of HANA Product Support team
- Multiplier for Customer Interaction Skills Workshops
- Technical Trainer for HANA HA100 course
- Facilitator for Design Thinking Workshops
- Promotional speaker, representing SAP, at Women Reboot program, promoting women returning to the IT industry.
- Excellent technical support for customers on wide ranging HANA issues through incident handling, Expert Chat and Schedule an Expert tools

- Produce a high volume of technical documentation for HANA to support KM 2.0 methodology
- Organizer of team schedules for weekend and EU-DP shifts

Key Skills:

- Project management
- Driver of Continuous Improvement of processes
- Presentation stills
- Technical analysis and problem solving
- Mentoring colleagues
- Customer interaction skills
- Technical Trainer
- Well organized and highly motivated
- Strive in a fast-paced working environment
- Design Thinking
- Highly driven to continuously upskill to adapt to new technologies

References available on request.